Louis Liu

150-1816-8034 | louisliu0422@outlook.com Shenzhen China github.com/vashavala

SUMMARY

More than 5 years experience of working in the fintech industry, developing and maintaining web applications across all sorts of client-side devices with various front-end technologies; Dedicated to performance optimization and UI/UX design achievement while coding swiftly and efficiently; Industrious and conscientious, possess a strong sense of responsibility and ownership at all times; Excellent communication and collaboration skills, ability to speak fluently in English and Chinese at the same time.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Thinkive Jun 2021 - Feb 2024

Senior FrontEnd Developer

Thinkive is a leading fintech software solutions provider in China

- Collaborated with a team of designers and back-end developers to develop a web platform for creating and editing financial short videos with React and TypeScript, which generated millions of short videos throughout thousands of financial companies, institutions, and individuals.
- Built infrastructure for several departments of the company, generated and iterated front-end components for our company's common library, and highly increased the development speed of non-customized projects all around the company.
- · Provided technical support and consultation around different departments, participated and assisted in dozens of projects.
- · Mentored junior developers in development processes, providing solutions, best practices, and code reviews.

Simuwang Sep 2018 - Apr 2021

FrontEnd Developer

Simuwang is one of the greatest private equity firms in China

- Building web applications for high net worth clients, buyers, and fund managers all around the world, providing them web applications with top-of-the-line designs and smoothest experience.
- Refactored a 3-year-old official website from Vue to Nuxt for better SEO, Server-side rendering almost doubled the web traffic.
- Integrated all the common services, functionalities, and components into a new project, and managed it by git submodule, reducing the amount of code by roughly about 30%.
- Dedicated to performance optimization in various angles on the official website with millions of traffic, resulting in a 180% increase in loading speed thus improving huge client-side acquisition and retention.
- Cooperated with the anti-crawler department, and blocked almost 98% of the web crawler by using special front-end technologies.
- Developed in cooperation with great banks such as ICBC and CMB etc., built up 10+ projects including content management system(PC), mobile application, hybrid H5 in IOS/Android, and mini-program.

EDUCATION

Shaoguan University Sep 2015 - Jun 2019

Information and Computing Science - Bachelor

SKILLS LIST

- HTML & CSS
- · Sass, Less, Stylus
- JQuery, Bootstrap
- React, Redux, Nextjs, MUI, Ant Design
- · Vue3, Pinia, Nuxtjs, Element Plus
- JavaScript, ES6[^], TypeScript
- Responsive Design
- Content Management System
- Git, Command Line Tools
- Web Performance Optimization
- Testing & Debugging
- SEO Fundamentals